Hello English learners.
各位英语学习者，大家好。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we have an elementary lesson for you and we are at the supermarket.
今天我们为大家准备了一节初级课程，场景是在超市。
That's right.
没错。
We're at the grocery store and we're going to learn some language you can use when you
我们在杂货店，要学习一些当你
want to pay for your groceries.
想为杂货付款时可以使用的语言。
So this lesson was requested by one of our users that wanted vocabulary and different
这节课是由我们的一位用户请求的，他想要学习超市里
phrases that are used in the supermarket when the person is about to pay for all the things
当顾客准备为所有需要的东西付款时
they need.
会用到的词汇和不同短语。
That's right.
没错。
And we also have some great language that the person who is actually selling the groceries
而且我们还有一些很棒的语言，是实际卖杂货的人
can use.
可以使用的。
All right.
好的。
So let's listen to our dialogue for the first time and see what happens.
那么让我们第一次听一下对话，看看发生了什么。
Excuse me, sir.
打扰一下，先生。
This is the express checkout lane for people who have 15 items or fewer.
这是快速结账通道，专为购买15件或以下商品的顾客设置。
It looks like you have more than 15 items there.
看起来您这里不止15件商品。
Oh, come on.
哦，别这样。
I have 16 items.
我有16件商品。
Cut me some slack, will you?
通融一下，行吗？
Fine.
好吧。
Please place your items on the belt and push your shopping cart through.
请把您的商品放在传送带上，然后把购物车推过去。
Do you prefer paper or plastic?
您喜欢纸袋还是塑料袋？
Plastic.
塑料袋。
I also have a couple of coupons.
我还有一些优惠券。
No problem.
没问题。
I'll take those.
我来处理那些。
Sir, these coupons expired yesterday.
先生，这些优惠券昨天就过期了。
Darn.
该死。
Oh, well, I guess it's just not my day.
哦，好吧，看来我今天运气不好。
Thanks anyway.
还是谢谢了。
Do you have a club card or will it be cash?
您有会员卡还是付现金？
Yeah, I got a club card.
有，我有会员卡。
Here you go.
给你。
Will this be debit or credit?
这是借记卡还是信用卡？
Debit, please.
借记卡，谢谢。
Also, can I get cash back?
另外，我能取点现金吗？
$50 would be great.
50美元就好了。
Yeah, sure.
好的，当然可以。
Your total is $78.33.
您的总金额是78.33美元。
Here's your receipt.
这是您的收据。
Have a nice day.
祝您愉快。
Well, we can see in this dialogue that the guy was able to buy his food and, you know,
嗯，在这个对话中我们可以看到，那个人成功买到了食物，而且，
they were using some really interesting, helpful language.
他们使用了一些非常有趣、有用的语言。
That's right.
没错。
So why don't we look at this language now in Language Takeaway.
那么我们现在在“语言要点”环节来看看这些语言吧。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, we have six words for you today.
好的，今天我们准备了六个单词。
And the first one, the girl, the cashier says, this is the express checkout lane.
第一个，那个女孩，收银员说，这是快速结账通道。
All right, so checkout lane.
好的，结账通道。
The checkout lane.
结账通道。
So the checkout lane is the place where you get in line to pay for all the goods you bought.
结账通道就是你排队付款买的所有商品的地方。
Right, so the checkout lane.
对，就是结账通道。
Now, why did she say express checkout lane?
那么，她为什么说快速结账通道呢？
So in grocery stores or in supermarkets, sometimes you have a specific checkout lane that's faster.
在杂货店或超市里，有时会有专门的结账通道，速度更快。
Okay.
好的。
Because people have less things.
因为人们买的东西少。
So express is the faster checkout lane.
所以快速就是更快的结账通道。
Right, the faster one.
对，更快的那条。
All right, so next she tells the guy to put your items on the belt.
好的，接下来她告诉那个人把你的商品放在传送带上。
Okay, the belt.
好的，传送带。
The belt.
传送带。
A belt.
So you think about belt as the thing you put around your waist.
你会想到腰带是系在腰上的东西。
To keep your pants up.
用来提裤子。
Right, but in a supermarket, the belt is the moving table that you put your groceries on
对，但在超市里，传送带是移动的台面，你把杂货放上去，
so the cashier starts to pass them through.
收银员就开始扫描它们。
Okay, so the belt.
好的，所以是传送带。
Okay, the belt.
好的，传送带。
Put your groceries on the belt.
把你的杂货放在传送带上。
And then the guy said that he had a couple of coupons.
然后那个人说他有一些优惠券。
Coupons.
优惠券。
A coupon.
一张优惠券。
Okay, so what is a coupon?
好的，什么是优惠券？
A coupon is a piece of paper you can use to get a discount.
优惠券是一张可以用来获得折扣的纸。
All right, so it has a discount on it.
好的，所以上面有折扣。
A discount for one thing.
针对某件商品的折扣。
So maybe you buy some apples and you get 10% off one kind of apple.
比如你买苹果，某种苹果可以打九折。
Very good, coupons.
非常好，优惠券。
Now he presented these coupons and she said they were expired.
现在他出示了这些优惠券，她说它们过期了。
The coupons expired yesterday.
这些优惠券昨天过期了。
Expired.
过期了。
To expire.
过期。
All right, so to expire.
好的，过期。
That means to be older than the date when you can use them.
意思是超过了可以使用它们的日期。
Right, so why don't we listen to some other examples of how we can use expired so we can
对，那么我们听一些其他如何使用“过期”的例子，这样我们
understand a little bit better.
能更好地理解。
Example one.
例子一。
I'm sorry, sir.
对不起，先生。
This credit card expired five years ago.
这张信用卡五年前就过期了。
You can't use it anymore.
您不能再用了。
Example two.
例子二。
My driver's license expires in a month, so I have to get it renewed.
我的驾照一个月后过期，所以我得去续期。
Example three.
例子三。
Don't drink that.
别喝那个。
The milk has expired.
牛奶已经过期了。
Okay, so we can see his coupons expired, so they were too old and he couldn't use them
好的，所以我们可以看到他的优惠券过期了，它们太旧了，他不能再用了。
anymore.
完全正确。
Exactly.
现在，最后她问他是否想用会员卡或现金支付。
And now, finally, she asked him if he wants to pay with his club card or cash.
会员卡。
So club card.
Club card.
会员卡。
What's a club card?
什么是会员卡？
So in some supermarkets, you can receive a special type of credit card that you can only
在一些超市里，你可以收到一种特殊的信用卡，只能
use for grocery shopping.
用于购买杂货。
And only in that store.
而且只在那家店使用。
Right.
对。
So that is a club card.
那就是会员卡。
All right, so a club card.
好的，会员卡。
Okay, so he's going to pay with a card, but he also asked for some cash back.
好的，所以他要用卡支付，但他还要求取一些现金。
Cash back.
现金返还。
Could I get cash back?
我能取现金吗？
Cash back.
现金返还。
Now, what's he talking about?
现在，他在说什么？
Can he get cash back?
他能取现金吗？
He's paying with a card.
他正在用卡支付。
What does he want to do?
他想做什么？
Well, what happens is sometimes, suppose your groceries cost $20.
嗯，有时候会发生这种情况，假设你的杂货花了20美元。
So instead of charging $20 to your credit card or your club card, you say, okay, put
所以不是从你的信用卡或会员卡里扣20美元，你说，好的，扣
$70.
70美元。
So then the cashier can give you $50 back.
然后收银员可以给你50美元现金。
So you can have cash in your pocket.
这样你口袋里就有现金了。
So instead of going to the ATM, you can get your money in one spot.
所以不用去自动取款机，你可以一次性拿到钱。
Exactly.
完全正确。
All right.
好的。
So that's cash back.
那就是现金返还。
Interesting.
有意思。
We're going to hear this one more time in the dialogue, but let's slow it down a little
我们会在对话中再听一次，但让我们放慢一点速度，
so we can understand better.
这样我们能更好地理解。
Excuse me, sir.
打扰一下，先生。
This is the express checkout lane for people that have 15 items or fewer.
这是快速结账通道，专为购买15件或以下商品的顾客设置。
It looks like you have more than 15 items there.
看起来您这里不止15件商品。
Oh, come on.
哦，别这样。
I have 16 items.
我有16件商品。
Get me some slack, will you?
通融一下，行吗？
Fine.
好吧。
Please place your items on the belt and push your shopping cart through.
请把您的商品放在传送带上，然后把购物车推过去。
Do you prefer paper or plastic?
您喜欢纸袋还是塑料袋？
Plastic.
塑料袋。
I also have a couple of coupons.
我还有一些优惠券。
No problem.
没问题。
I'll take those.
我来处理那些。
Sir, these coupons expired yesterday.
先生，这些优惠券昨天就过期了。
Darn.
该死。
Oh, well, I guess it's just not my day.
哦，好吧，看来我今天运气不好。
Thanks, anyway.
还是谢谢了。
Do you have a club card or will it be cash?
您有会员卡还是付现金？
Yeah, I got a club card.
有，我有会员卡。
Here you go.
给你。
Will this be debit or credit?
这是借记卡还是信用卡？
Debit, please.
借记卡，谢谢。
Also, can I get cash back?
另外，我能取点现金吗？
$50 would be great.
50美元就好了。
Yeah, sure.
好的，当然可以。
Your total is $78.33.
您的总金额是78.33美元。
Here is your receipt.
这是您的收据。
Have a nice day.
祝您愉快。
Thank you.
谢谢。
All right.
好的。
So now that we've listened to the dialogue for the second time, it's time for us to take
现在我们听了第二遍对话，是时候看看
a look at some phrases in Fluency Builder.
“流利度提升”环节的一些短语了。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升。
Okay, we have three phrases for you now.
好的，今天我们准备了三个短语。
Well, the guy was not having a very good day, was he?
嗯，那个人今天运气不太好，是吧？
So he couldn't go in the express checkout lane and he says, cut me some slack.
所以他不能走快速结账通道，他说，通融一下。
Cut me some slack.
通融一下。
To cut someone some slack.
对某人通融一下。
All right.
好的。
Now, this is an interesting and very informal phrase.
现在，这是一个有趣且非常非正式的短语。
So before we explain it, why don't we listen to a couple of other examples?
所以在解释之前，我们听几个其他例子吧。
Example one.
例子一。
Cut me some slack.
通融一下。
I'm only two minutes late.
我只迟到了两分钟。
Example two.
例子二。
My wife just had a baby and I'm so tired.
我妻子刚生了孩子，我太累了。
Cut me some slack.
通融一下。
I'll send you the report tomorrow.
我明天把报告发给你。
Example three.
例子三。
Emily had a really bad week.
Emily这周过得很糟糕。
I think you should cut her some slack.
我觉得你应该对她通融一下。
Okay, I think I can understand it means relax the rules a little bit.
好的，我想我能理解，意思是放松一点规则。
Right.
对。
So don't be so strict on me.
所以别对我那么严格。
Yeah, don't be so hard.
是的，别那么苛刻。
Now, I know this phrase actually comes from mountain climbing.
现在，我知道这个短语实际上来自登山。
Oh, because of the rope.
哦，因为绳子。
Yeah.
是的。
So it's just, it's like saying the slack is loose rope.
所以就像是在说，松弛就是松的绳子。
So he's just saying, give me a little bit more freedom.
所以他只是说，给我多一点自由。
Give me more freedom.
给我更多自由。
Oh, interesting.
哦，有意思。
Yep.
是的。
To cut somebody some slack.
对某人通融一下。
Well, now the cashier asked him a question.
嗯，现在收银员问了他一个问题。
She says, do you prefer paper or plastic?
她说，你喜欢纸袋还是塑料袋？
Do you prefer paper or plastic?
你喜欢纸袋还是塑料袋？
Paper or plastic.
纸袋还是塑料袋。
Now, this is the common cliche phrase that any grocery store cashier will use, right?
这是每个杂货店收银员都会用的老套话，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Paper or plastic what?
纸袋还是塑料袋什么？
Bags.
袋子。
Paper or plastic bags.
纸袋还是塑料袋。
All right.
好的。
So you'll hear this all the time in every grocery store.
所以你在每个杂货店都会经常听到这句话。
Do you want paper or plastic?
你想要纸袋还是塑料袋？
Right.
没错。
So you can choose plastic bags or paper bags.
所以你可以选择塑料袋或纸袋。
Okay.
好的。
Remember this one because when you get it right, you'll sound really native-like.
记住这个，因为如果你说对了，听起来会非常地道。
Very good.
非常好。
And our last phrase, since he wasn't really having a good day, he said, it's just not
我们最后一个短语，因为他那天不太顺利，他说，
my day.
今天真不顺。
It's just not my day.
It's not my day.
今天不顺。
Okay, so when it's not your day, it means the day has been hard.
好的，所以当“今天不顺”时，意思是这一天很艰难。
You've not really lucky.
你运气不太好。
Yeah.
是的。
It's not a good day for you.
对你来说不是个好日子。
Not a good day.
不是个好日子。
All right.
好的。
So let's listen to the dialogue for the last time and then we'll come back and talk a little
那我们最后听一遍对话，然后回来聊聊
bit about grocery stores in America.
美国的杂货店。
Excuse me, sir.
打扰一下，先生。
This is the express checkout lane for people that have 15 items or fewer.
这是快速结账通道，只限15件或以下商品的顾客。
It looks like you have more than 15 items there.
看起来您那里不止15件商品。
Oh, come on.
哦，别这样。
I have 16 items.
我有16件商品。
Cut me some slack, will you?
通融一下，行吗？
Fine.
好吧。
Please place your items on the belt and push your shopping cart through.
请把商品放在传送带上，然后把购物车推过去。
Do you prefer paper or plastic?
您喜欢纸袋还是塑料袋？
Plastic.
塑料袋。
I also have a couple of coupons.
我还有一些优惠券。
No problem.
没问题。
I'll take those.
我来收。
Sir, these coupons expired yesterday.
先生，这些优惠券昨天就过期了。
Darn.
该死。
Oh, well, I guess it's just not my day.
哦，好吧，我想今天真不顺。
Thanks anyway.
还是谢谢了。
Do you have a club card or will it be cash?
您有会员卡吗，还是付现金？
Yeah, I got a club card.
有，我有会员卡。
Here you go.
给你。
Will this be debit or credit?
用借记卡还是信用卡？
Debit please.
借记卡，谢谢。
Also, can I get cash back?
另外，我能取点现金吗？
$50 would be great.
50美元就好了。
Yeah, sure.
好的，当然。
Your total is $78.33.
您的总金额是78.33美元。
Here's your receipt.
这是您的收据。
Have a nice day.
祝您有美好的一天。
One interesting thing I know about grocery stores in America is that the people who are
我知道美国杂货店一个有趣的事情是，
the cashiers are very often students.
收银员通常是学生。
Right.
没错。
It's a very popular summer job or part-time job of college students.
这是大学生很常见的暑期工作或兼职。
Or even in my hometown, it was the most common job for high school students.
甚至在我家乡，这是高中生最常见的工作。
After school, if you went to the grocery store between 4 o'clock and 9 o'clock at night,
放学后，如果你在晚上4点到9点之间去杂货店，
every single cashier would be a high school student.
每个收银员都会是高中生。
And the interesting thing is that the cashiers are usually women, right?
有趣的是，收银员通常是女性，对吧？
Yeah, always the high school girls who are the cashiers.
是的，总是高中女生当收银员。
And so the high school boys would be working in the back, maybe in the warehouse carrying
而高中男生会在后面工作，可能在仓库搬箱子
boxes or stocking the shelves.
或者上货架。
So putting the cans on the shelves, right?
就是把罐头放到货架上，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
It's a very popular part-time job for students in the United States, but also coupons are
这是美国学生很常见的兼职工作，但优惠券
very popular in America.
在美国也很流行。
Yeah.
是的。
What is it about coupons?
优惠券有什么特别的？
Well, usually, for example, in the Sunday newspaper, you will receive a lot of coupons.
嗯，通常，比如在周日报纸上，你会收到很多优惠券。
You go to the grocery store and you have all these coupons for like cookies or a promotion
你去杂货店，带着这些优惠券，比如买饼干或者
on some type of soda or drink.
某种汽水或饮料的促销。
So it's very popular.
所以这很流行。
People go grocery shopping and then present all these coupons.
人们去杂货店购物，然后出示所有这些优惠券。
And actually, you can end up saving a good amount of money.
实际上，你最终能省下不少钱。
I know the coupons are usually like, save two cents or save 25 cents.
我知道优惠券通常像省两分钱或省25分钱。
But I guess if you put all of those together, you can save money.
但我想如果你把所有优惠券加起来，就能省钱。
It's interesting because people actually will buy that product just because they have a
有趣的是，人们真的会因为有一张优惠券
coupon for it.
而买那个产品。
Coupons and high school checkout girls.
优惠券和高中收银员女孩。
Well, guys, thanks for listening to this show.
好了，各位，感谢收听本期节目。
Now, remember, if you have any questions about the language we were talking about in this
现在，记住，如果你对我们节目中讨论的语言有任何问题，
show, please visit our website at EnglishPod.com.
请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Right.
没错。
Leave all your questions and comments there.
在那里留下你的所有问题和评论。
And also, if you have any other suggestions or any doubts, please let us know and we'll
另外，如果你有其他建议或疑问，请告诉我们，
see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
So thanks for listening and until next time.
所以感谢收听，下次再见。
Goodbye.
再见。